William Schultz

Email: linkedinwill23@gmail.com
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/williamschultz01
Portfolio: https://tinyurl.com/ynm57mqc
Location: St. Paul, Minnesota

Profile Summary

Creative and experienced Web Specialist with over three years of experience as a Content Strategist and Project Manager for State of MN government websites, Web Developer for front-end applications, Content management system administrator for MN agencies and non-profits, and Data Analyst for a large matrix healthcare organization.

Web Specialist Qualifications

Website Administration

- Led web best practices for the MN Department of Employment and Economic Development's "Thriving in the North" economic development website project, MN Combined Charities Campaign, Public Health Law Center and MN Management & Budget.
- Successfully managed and maintained content management systems in a government, non-profit, and corporate environment. Responsibilities included content creation, providing CMS training and improving webpage quality with a focus on accessibility, information architecture, SEO and performance.
- Designed web applications and responsive websites as web developer with technical front-end development skills utilizing React, Javascript (Typescript), CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop, Node.is, PostgreSQL and RESTful APIs.
- Digital analytics and reporting experience with the HealthPartners organization utilizing Power BI dashboards to monitor data pipeline performance. Additional Data Analyst experience included data modeling within the Databricks (Azure) cloudplatform, writing SQL to analyze data in Oracle databases, monitoring data quality with Python (Great Expectations) and working on an Agile team to produce positive business results.

Content Strategy & Management

- Web content creator with experience using CMS templates on multiple platforms that include: Adobe Experience Manager (AEM), Tridion, Drupal, and DotNetNuke (DNN).
- Partnered with marketing managers, business development staff, social media specialists, writers, and business analysts to align the economic development website content with the MN "Thriving in the North Campaign".

Content Creation & Marketing Communications

- Experienced plain language writer and editor for State of MN government websites who holds a Master's Degree in Fine Writing from Hamline University.
- Technical and strategic personalization expert who designed components utilizing the Dynamic Yield platform for web content aimed at acquiring customers from the HealthPartners Medicare campaign pages.

Skills & Expertise Areas

- Web Page Layouts & Design UX/UI web developer with responsive design skills utilizing HTML and CSS.
- Project Management Certified Professional Project Manager (University of St. Thomas).
- Website Accessibility Well-versed in WCAG guidelines established by the Office of Accessibility at Minnesota IT Services.

• **Technical Writing** - HealthPartners Data Informatics process documentation specialist who utilized the Confluence platform for organizational communication.

Platforms & Technical Languages

- · Content Management Systems (AEM, Tridion, Drupal, and DNN)
- Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Lucid Chart (Process Mapping Design)
- Python (Pandas, Object-Oriented Programming, Modules, ETL Pipelines, Great Expectations)
- PostgreSQL & PL/SQL (Data Analysis and API Development)
- · Microsoft Excel & Word (Project Plans, Data Analysis and Documentation)
- Power BI (Dashboards for Reporting)
- · PowerPoint & Canva (Presenting to a Large Group, Training Staff)
- · Agile Methodologies & JIRA (Experienced with Scrum Ceremonies and Kanban Boards)

Education

- Master's Degree, Fine Writing, Hamline University, St. Paul, MN
- · Bachelor's Degree, Creative Writing, Augsburg University, Minneapolis, MN
- Certified Professional Project Manager (CPPM), University of St. Thomas, Minneapolis, MN
- · Google IT Automation with Python, Certification
- Mini-MBA, University of St. Thomas, Minneapolis, MN

Professional Experience

Data Analyst, HealthPartners, Bloomington, MN - 2022-2024

- DevDays technical leader who successfully guided the team to integrate sentiment analysis and machine learning into our
 project to improve patient care related to orthopedic knee surgeries.
- Initiated solutions for data informatics ETL processes by developing shared modules in Python, creating API solutions for third-party vendor access to claims data, and overseeing data governance within the Databricks cloud migration project.
- Managed EIM Operations Divisional ServiceNow tickets by developing performance tracking spreadsheets, triaging issues for resolution, troubleshooting technical requests across multiple platforms and communicating effectively to stakeholders.

Web Content Specialist & Developer, HealthPartners, Bloomington, MN - 2021-2022

- Utilized the Adobe Workfront platform to complete marketing requests for Medicare campaigns, website landing page creation and quality assurance tasks.
- · Led the template creation development process for website components in the Dynamic Yield personalization platform.
- Took the lead on researching website integration solutions with the LinkedIn platform and presented the educational materials to the team.

Web Content Specialist, Colder Products Company, Roseville, MN 2020-2021

- Project coordinator for mapping Adobe Experience Manager website components for the corporate initiatives to migrate CMS platforms.
- Increased website accessibility for e-commerce customers through creating WCAG compatible web components and utilized the SiteImprove platform to implement accessibility improvement recommendations.

• Increased employee communication and morale by creating the e-monthly newsletter to feature vital information about events and company initiatives.

Digital Communications Coordinator, MN Department of Employment & Economic Development, St. Paul, MN 2018-2018

- Project Manager who successfully create an economic development website to actively promote business in Minnesota as part of the "Thriving in the North" annual marketing campaign.
- Improved the incoming communication to the DEED business development office by gathering requirements from stakeholders, setting up online forms and partnering with IT on quality assurance and web-launch testing.
- Lead digital accessibility efforts to improve access to DEED website users through building screen-reader compatible website pages, color contrast adjusted UX/UI designs and writing plain language content.

Digital Content Producer, Public Health Law Center, St. Paul, MN 2016-2017

- Web developer responsible for a map application for stakeholders to search for data related to healthcare research. The application assisted with the annual non-profit funding efforts of the organization.
- Web content specialist who successfully maintained the organization's website, developed pages inline with marketing brand standards and wrote copy based on marketing team input.

Information Officer, MN Management & Budget, St, Paul, MN 2013-2014

- Project Manager whose revamped combined charities website helped raise upwards of one million dollars for United Way charities.
- Project Coordinator for building new website content for MMB divisions as part of the CMS platform migration project.
- Content Management System technical trainer who worked cross-divisionally to successfully empower stakeholders to update their web content through documentation and one-on-one training sessions.